<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://NENmSIS.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>The NENmSIS project Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://NENmSIS.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>The NENmSIS project Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://NENmSIS.github.io/img/avatargithub.jpg</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulnerability Research]]></title>
        <id>Vulnerability Research</id>
        <link href="https://NENmSIS.github.io/blog/Vulnerability Research"/>
        <updated>2022-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Categories of vulnerabilities]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Categories of vulnerabilities</h3><ul><li>Operating System: found within Operating Systems (OSs).</li><li>(Mis)Configuration-based: incorrectly configured application or service.</li><li>Weak or Default Credentials: Applications and services that have an element of authentication will come with default credentials when installed.</li><li>Application Logic: the result of poorly designed applications. </li><li>Human-Factor: vulnerabilities that leverage human behaviour.</li></ul><h3>Scoring vulnerabilities</h3><ul><li>Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS)</li><li>Vulnerability Priority Rating (VPR)</li></ul><h3>Vulnerability databases</h3><ul><li><a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/full-listing">NVD</a></li><li><a href="https://www.exploit-db.com/">Exploit Database</a></li></ul><h3>Finding manual exploits</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.rapid7.com/db/">Rapid7</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/">Github</a></li><li><strong>searchsploit</strong> on kali, offline</li></ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>NENmSIS</name>
            <uri>https://NENmSIS.github.io</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[File-system permissions]]></title>
        <id>File-system permissions</id>
        <link href="https://NENmSIS.github.io/blog/File-system permissions"/>
        <updated>2022-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an interesting topic to talk about with the aim of understanding the Unix permissions.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an interesting topic to talk about with the aim of understanding the Unix permissions.</p><h2>Notation of traditional Unix permissions</h2><h2>Symbolic notation</h2><p>The most common form, as used by the following command, is symbolic notation. </p><pre><code>ls -l 
</code></pre><p>The firs set represents the <em>user</em> class. The second set represents the <em>group</em> class. The third set represents the <em>others</em> class.
Each of the three characters represent the read, write and execute permissions.</p><ul><li><em>r</em> if reading is permitted, - if is not</li><li><em>w</em> if writting is permitted, - if is not</li><li><em>x</em> if execution is permitted, - if is not</li></ul><p>Example: <strong>-rwxr-xr-x</strong>: a regular file whose user class has full permissions and whose group and others classes have only the read and execute permissions.</p><p>To represent the <strong><em>setuid</em></strong>, <strong><em>setgid</em></strong> and <strong><em>sticky</em></strong> attributes, the executable character ( x or -) is modified. Though these attributes affect the overall file, not only users in one class, the <strong><em>setuid</em></strong> attribute modifies the executable character in the triad for the user, the <strong><em>setgid</em></strong> attribute modifies the executable character in the triad for the group and the <strong><em>sticky</em></strong> attribure modifies the executable character in the triad for others. For the <strong><em>setuid</em></strong> or <strong><em>setgid</em></strong> attributes, in the first or second triad, the <em>x</em> becomes <em>s</em> and the - becomes <em>s</em>. For the <strong><em>sticky</em></strong> attribute, in the third triad, the <em>x</em> becomes <em>t</em> and the - becomes <em>T</em>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>NENmSIS</name>
            <uri>https://NENmSIS.github.io</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bienvenidos]]></title>
        <id>Bienvenidos</id>
        <link href="https://NENmSIS.github.io/blog/Bienvenidos"/>
        <updated>2021-12-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducción a la web]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Introducción a la web</h2><p>Si estáis leyendo este post, es porque la web ya se ha publicado y el proyecto acaba de empezar. Desde este momento, todos los artículos que se suban serán parte del proyecto personal de ciberseguridad, economía e idiomas que voy a desarrollar.</p><p>Este proyecto nace de la necesidad de documentar el progreso y los conocimientos aprendidos con el objetivo de favorecer el desarrollo de aquellas personas que puedan encontrarse en la misma situación. A su vez, una vez quede documentada la información, su acceso reiterado se simplifica de manera significativa, permitiendo aumentar la velocidad de aprendizaje y disminuir los errores. Además, toda aquella información adicional relativa a distintos artículos creados que mejore la calidad de la información expuesta, será añadida con posterioridad.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>NENmSIS</name>
            <uri>https://NENmSIS.github.io</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>